let questions = [
  {
    question: "What is the capital of Finland?",
    option1: "Turku",
    option2: "Helsinki",
    option3: "Oulu",
    option4: "Vaasa",
    answer: "Helsinki",
  },
  {
    question: "What color does yellow and green make?",
    option1: "Lime",
    option2: "Ocean mist",
    option3: "Tangerine",
    option4: "Maroon",
    answer: "Lime",
  },
  {
    question: "Fathometer is used to measure?",
    option1: "Earthquakes",
    option2: "Rainfall",
    option3: "Sound intensity",
    option4: "Ocean depth",
    answer: "Ocean depth",
  },
  {
    question: "Golf player Vijay Singh belongs to which country?",
    option1: "USA",
    option2: "Fiji",
    option3: "India",
    option4: "UK",
    answer: "Fiji",
  },
  {
    question: "Which is a green planet in the solar system?",
    option1: "Pluto",
    option2: "Venus",
    option3: "Uranus",
    option4: "Mars",
    answer: "Uranus",
  },
  {
    question: "An astronaut in outer space will observe sky as?",
    option1: "White",
    option2: "Black",
    option3: "Blue",
    option4: "Red",
    answer: "Black",
  },
  {
    question: "Which is considered as the biggest port of India?",
    option1: "Kolkata",
    option2: "Cochin",
    option3: "Chennai",
    option4: "Mumbai",
    answer: "Mumbai",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Study of human beauty called?",
    option1: "Argology",
    option2: "Kalology",
    option3: "Agrostology",
    option4: "Oncology",
    answer: "Kalology",
  },
  {
    question: "Yellow colour of papaya is due to?",
    option1: "Caricaxanthin",
    option2: "Carotene",
    option3: "Lycopene",
    option4: "Papain",
    answer: "Caricaxanthin",
  },
  {
    question: "The Computer size was very large in?",
    option1: "Fourth Generation",
    option2: "Third Generation",
    option3: "Second Generation",
    option4: "First Generation",
    answer: "First Generation",
  },
  {
    question: "In 1768, Captain James Cook set out to explore which ocean?",
    option1: "Pacific Ocean",
    option2: "Atlantic Ocean",
    option3: "Indian Ocean",
    option4: "Arctic Ocean",
    answer: "Pacific Ocean",
  },
  {
    question: "What is actually electricity?",
    option1: "A flow of water",
    option2: "A flow of air",
    option3: "A flow of atoms",
    option4: "A flow of electrons",
    answer: "A flow of electrons",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not an international organisation?",
    option1: "FIFA",
    option2: "NATO",
    option3: "FBI",
    option4: "ASEAN",
    answer: "FBI",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following disorders is the fear of being alone?",
    option1: "Agoraphobia",
    option2: "Aerophobia",
    option3: "Acrophobia",
    option4: "Arachnophobia",
    answer: "Agoraphobia",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is a song by the German heavy metal band “Scorpions”?",
    option1: "Stairway to Heaven",
    option2: "Wind of Change",
    option3: "Don't Stop Me Now",
    option4: "Hey Jude",
    answer: "Wind of Change",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the speed of sound?",
    option1: "120 km/h",
    option2: "1,200 km/h",
    option3: "400 km/h",
    option4: "700 km/h",
    answer: "1,200 km/h",
  },
  {
    question: "What do we call a newly hatched butterfly?",
    option1: "A moth",
    option2: "A butter",
    option3: "A caterpillar",
    option4: "A chrysalis",
    answer: "A caterpillar",
  },
  {
    question: "In total, how many novels were written by the Bronte sisters?",
    option1: "4",
    option2: "5",
    option3: "6",
    option4: "7",
    answer: "7",
  },
  {
    question: "Which did Viking people use as money?",
    option1: "Rune stones",
    option2: "Jewellery",
    option3: "Seal skins",
    option4: "Wool",
    answer: "Jewellery",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the first country to use tanks in combat during World War I?",
    option1: "France",
    option2: "Japan",
    option3: "Britain",
    option4: "Germany",
    answer: "Britain",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the main component of the sun?",
    option1: "Liquid lava",
    option2: "Gas",
    option3: "Molten iron",
    option4: "Rock",
    answer: "Gas",
  },
  {
    question: "Goulash is a type of beef soup in which country?",
    option1: "Hungary",
    option2: "Czech Republic",
    option3: "Slovakia",
    option4: "Ireland",
    answer: "Hungary",
  },
  {
    question: "Which two months are named after Emperors of the Roman Empire?",
    option1: "January and February",
    option2: "March and April",
    option3: "May and June",
    option4: "July and August",
    answer: "July and August",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following animals can run the fastest?",
    option1: "Cheetah",
    option2: "Leopard",
    option3: "Tiger",
    option4: "Lion",
    answer: "Cheetah",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the most points that a player can score with a single throw in darts?",
    option1: "20",
    option2: "40",
    option3: "60",
    option4: "80",
    answer: "60",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following actors was the first one to play James Bond?",
    option1: "Timothy Dalton",
    option2: "Roger Moore",
    option3: "Sean Connery",
    option4: "George Lazenby",
    answer: "Sean Connery",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following songs was the top-selling hit in 2019?",
    option1: "Someone You Loved",
    option2: "Old Town Road",
    option3: "I Don't Care",
    option4: "Bad Guy",
    answer: "Someone You Loved",
  },
  {
    question: "In which country is Transylvania?",
    option1: "Bulgaria",
    option2: "Romania",
    option3: "Croatia",
    option4: "Serbia",
    answer: "Romania",
  },
  {
    question: "Which football club does Jordan Henderson play for?",
    option1: "Liverpool",
    option2: "Manchester City",
    option3: "Tottenham Hotspur",
    option4: "Chelsea",
    answer: "Liverpool",
  },
  {
    question: "The two biggest exporters of beers in Europe are Germany and?",
    option1: "Spain",
    option2: "France",
    option3: "Italy",
    option4: "Belgium",
    answer: "Belgium",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The phrase: ”I think, therefore I am” was coined by which philosopher?",
    option1: "Socrates",
    option2: "Plato",
    option3: "Aristotle",
    option4: "Descartes",
    answer: "Descartes",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the series “Game of Thrones”, Winterfell is the ancestral home of which family?",
    option1: "The Lannisters",
    option2: "The Starks",
    option3: "The Tully's",
    option4: "The Targaryens",
    answer: "The Starks",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is known as the Patron Saint of Spain?",
    option1: "St Patrick",
    option2: "St Benedict",
    option3: "St James",
    option4: "St John",
    answer: "St James",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the term “SOS” commonly stand for?",
    option1: "Save Our Sheep",
    option2: "Save Our Ship",
    option3: "Save Our Seal",
    option4: "Save Our Souls",
    answer: "Save Our Souls",
  },
  {
    question: "Which company is known for publishing the Mario video game?",
    option1: "Xbox",
    option2: "Nintendo",
    option3: "SEGA",
    option4: "Electronic Arts",
    answer: "Nintendo",
  },
  {
    question:
      "We often use sodium bicarbonate in the kitchen. What is its other name?",
    option1: "Vinegar",
    option2: "Sugar",
    option3: "Salt",
    option4: "Baking soda",
    answer: "Baking soda",
  },
  {
    question: "Which was the first film by Disney to be produced in colour?",
    option1: "Toy Story",
    option2: "Sleeping Beauty",
    option3: "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs",
    option4: "Cinderella",
    answer: "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the first book of the Old Testament in the Bible?",
    option1: "Exodus",
    option2: "Genesis",
    option3: "Proverbs",
    option4: "Matthew",
    answer: "Genesis",
  },
  {
    question: "How many time zones are there in total in the world?",
    option1: "8",
    option2: "16",
    option3: "24",
    option4: "32",
    answer: "24",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the rarest type of blood in the human body?",
    option1: "AB negative",
    option2: "O positive",
    option3: "B negative",
    option4: "A positive",
    answer: "AB negative",
  },
  {
    question: "Cu is the chemical symbol for which element?",
    option1: "Oxygen",
    option2: "Copper",
    option3: "Zinc",
    option4: "Helium",
    answer: "Copper",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who sang the title song for the latest Bond film, No Time to Die?",
    option1: "Adele",
    option2: "Billie Eilish",
    option3: "Sam Smith",
    option4: "Ed Sheeran",
    answer: "Billie Eilish",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which flies a green, white, and orange (in that order) tricolour flag?",
    option1: "Ivory Coast",
    option2: "Ireland",
    option3: "Hungary",
    option4: "Italy",
    answer: "Italy",
  },
  {
    question: "What company makes the Xperia model of smartphone?",
    option1: "Samsung",
    option2: "Nokia",
    option3: "Sony",
    option4: "Apple",
    answer: "Sony",
  },
  {
    question: "Which city is home to the Brandenburg Gate?",
    option1: "Vienna",
    option2: "Zurich",
    option3: "Munich",
    option4: "Berlin",
    answer: "Berlin",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a fruit?",
    option1: "Rhubarb",
    option2: "Tomatoes",
    option3: "Avocados",
    option4: "Apple",
    answer: "Rhubarb",
  },
  {
    question: "Where was the first example of paper money used?",
    option1: "Turkey",
    option2: "Greece",
    option3: "China",
    option4: "Usa",
    answer: "China",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is generally considered the inventor of the motor car?",
    option1: "Karl Benz",
    option2: "Henry Ford",
    option3: "Henry M. Leland",
    option4: "Elon Musk",
    answer: "Karl Benz",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you were looking at Iguazu Falls, on what continent would you be?",
    option1: "Asia",
    option2: "Africa",
    option3: "South America",
    option4: "Europe",
    answer: "South America",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following languages has the longest alphabet?",
    option1: "Greek",
    option2: "Russian",
    option3: "Arabic",
    option4: "Perse",
    answer: "Russian",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the lead singer of the band The Who?",
    option1: "Roger Daltrey",
    option2: "Don Henley",
    option3: "Robert Plant",
    option4: "Elton John",
    answer: "Robert Plant",
  },
  {
    question: "What spirit is used in making a Tom Collins?",
    option1: "Vodka",
    option2: "Gin",
    option3: "Rum",
    option4: "Tequila",
    answer: "Gin",
  },
  {
    question: "The fear of insects is known as what?",
    option1: "Entomophobia",
    option2: "Arachnophobia",
    option3: "Ailurophobia",
    option4: "Cynophobia",
    answer: "Entomophobia",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the largest US state (by landmass)?",
    option1: "Texas",
    option2: "Alaska",
    option3: "California",
    option4: "Florida",
    answer: "Alaska",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Game of Thrones character is known as the Young Wolf?",
    option1: "Sansa Stark",
    option2: "Arya Stark",
    option3: "Eddard Stark",
    option4: "Robb Stark",
    answer: "Robb Stark",
  },
  {
    question: "What city hosted the 2002 Olympic Games?",
    option1: "Tokyo",
    option2: "Beijing",
    option3: "Sydney",
    option4: "Vancouver",
    answer: "Sydney",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How many plays do people (generally) believe that Shakespeare wrote?",
    option1: "27",
    option2: "37",
    option3: "47",
    option4: "17",
    answer: "37",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following was considered one of the Seven Ancient Wonders?",
    option1: "Colosseum",
    option2: "Great Wall of China",
    option3: "Colossus of Rhodes",
    option4: "Berlin Wall",
    answer: "Colossus of Rhodes",
  },
  {
    question: "Who directed the Academy award winning movie Gladiator?",
    option1: "Ridley Scott",
    option2: "James Cameron",
    option3: "Steven Soderbergh",
    option4: "Christopher Nolan",
    answer: "Ridley Scott",
  },
  {
    question: "How long did dinosaurs live on the earth?",
    option1: "100-150 million years",
    option2: "150-200 million years",
    option3: "200+ million years",
    option4: "300+ million years",
    answer: "150-200 million years",
  },
  {
    question: "What Italian city is famous for its system of canals?",
    option1: "Rome",
    option2: "Naples",
    option3: "Turin",
    option4: "Venice",
    answer: "Venice",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the strongest muscle in the human body?",
    option1: "Jaw",
    option2: "Heart",
    option3: "Glutes",
    option4: "Tongue",
    answer: "Jaw",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the longest running Broadway show ever?",
    option1: "Les Miserable",
    option2: "The Lion King",
    option3: "The Phantom of the Opera",
    option4: "Chicago",
    answer: "The Phantom of the Opera",
  },
  {
    question: "Where was tea invented?",
    option1: "England",
    option2: "China",
    option3: "Portual",
    option4: "Maroc",
    answer: "China",
  },
  {
    question: "Where was the earliest documented case of the Spanish flu?",
    option1: "USA",
    option2: "Spain",
    option3: "France",
    option4: "Mexico",
    answer: "USA",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following languages is NOT driven from Latin?",
    option1: "French",
    option2: "Portuguese",
    option3: "English",
    option4: "Spanish",
    answer: "English",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When did the government in Ireland grant women the right to vote?",
    option1: "1900",
    option2: "1918",
    option3: "1943",
    option4: "1959",
    answer: "1918",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which veggie was introduced by Oliver Cromwell to Dublin in 1649?",
    option1: "Broccoli",
    option2: "Beets",
    option3: "Potato",
    option4: "Cabbage",
    answer: "Cabbage",
  },
  {
    question: "Which shape are the typical orbits of comets?",
    option1: "Triangle",
    option2: "Elliptical",
    option3: "Rectangular",
    option4: "Circle",
    answer: "Elliptical",
  },
  {
    question:
      "There are 4 states of matter in physics: gas, liquid, solid, and …",
    option1: "Electron",
    option2: "Crystal",
    option3: "Plasma",
    option4: "Oxygen",
    answer: "Plasma",
  },
  {
    question: "How many colours are there in sunlight?",
    option1: "1",
    option2: "7",
    option3: "3",
    option4: "5",
    answer: "7",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which of the following environments can sound travel fastest?",
    option1: "Air",
    option2: "Liquid",
    option3: "Solid",
    option4: "Water",
    answer: "Solid",
  },
  {
    question: "Decibel or Db is the unit of measurement for what?",
    option1: "Light intensity",
    option2: "Loudness",
    option3: "Temperature",
    option4: "Mass",
    answer: "Loudness",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When an acid comes in contact with your skin, you should immediately wash it with what?",
    option1: "Water",
    option2: "Oil",
    option3: "Soap",
    option4: "Vinegar",
    answer: "Water",
  },
  {
    question: "What year was the very first model of the iPhone released?",
    option1: "2002",
    option2: "2005",
    option3: "2007",
    option4: "2003",
    answer: "2007",
  },
  {
    question: "What is often seen as the smallest unit of memory?",
    option1: "kilobyte",
    option2: "Megabyte",
    option3: "Gigabyte",
    option4: "Terabyte",
    answer: "kilobyte",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following ingredients is not normally used to brew beer?",
    option1: "Hops",
    option2: "Yeast",
    option3: "Malt",
    option4: "Vinegar",
    answer: "Vinegar",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the most densely populated U.S. state?",
    option1: "Connecticut",
    option2: "New Jersey",
    option3: "Rhode Island",
    option4: "Maryland",
    answer: "New Jersey",
  },
  {
    question:
      "King Philip II of Macedonia was assassinated in 336 B.C. and was succeeded by his son. Who was he?",
    option1: "Alexander the Great",
    option2: "Philip III",
    option3: "Diadochi",
    option4: "Antigonus II",
    answer: "Alexander the Great",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What group did Stephen Stills leave to form Crosby, Stills & Nash?",
    option1: "Blind Faith",
    option2: "Buffalo Springfield",
    option3: "The Spencer Davis Band",
    option4: "The Yardbirds",
    answer: "Buffalo Springfield",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Kazakhstan lies at approximately the same latitude as which other country?",
    option1: "Afghanistan",
    option2: "Nepal",
    option3: "Turkey",
    option4: "Mongolia",
    answer: "Mongolia",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Albert Einstein was a scientist famous for his work on physics. Where was he born?",
    option1: "Germany",
    option2: "United States",
    option3: "France",
    option4: "England",
    answer: "Germany",
  },
  {
    question: "Where in the US is the “Petrified Forest”?",
    option1: "Arkansas",
    option2: "California",
    option3: "Arizona",
    option4: "Nevada",
    answer: "Arizona",
  },
  {
    question:
      " Which former house painter began the Cubist movement with Picasso?",
    option1: "Gris",
    option2: "Braque",
    option3: "Cezanne",
    option4: "Renoir",
    answer: "Braque",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which former French colony was the first to achieve independence in Sub-Saharan Africa in 1958?",
    option1: "Mali",
    option2: "Algeria",
    option3: "Guinea",
    option4: "Cameroun",
    answer: "Guinea",
  },
  {
    question: "How fast can an ostrich run?",
    option1: "20 mph",
    option2: "30 mph",
    option3: "15 mph",
    option4: "40 mph",
    answer: "40 mph",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Caribbean island has the greatest area?",
    option1: "Jamaica",
    option2: "Cuba",
    option3: "Puerto Rico",
    option4: "Hispanola",
    answer: "Cuba",
  },
  {
    question: "Zulia is a province of which country?",
    option1: "Colombia",
    option2: "Brazil",
    option3: "Venezuela",
    option4: "Ecuador",
    answer: "Venezuela",
  },
  {
    question: "On the TV sitcom Seinfeld, what is Kramer's first name?",
    option1: "Cosmo",
    option2: "Kessler",
    option3: "Newman",
    option4: "Larry",
    answer: "Cosmo",
  },
  {
    question: "Steven Bochco was a creator of both “L.A. Law” and:",
    option1: "Life Goes On",
    option2: "Cagney and Lacey",
    option3: "Law and Order",
    option4: "Hill Street Blues",
    answer: "Hill Street Blues",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the capital of French Polynesia?",
    option1: "Praia",
    option2: "Papeete",
    option3: "Moroni",
    option4: "Cayenne",
    answer: "Papeete",
  },
  {
    question: "How much of your vision do you lose if you go blind in one eye?",
    option1: "50 percent",
    option2: "10 percent",
    option3: "20 percent",
    option4: "35 percent",
    answer: "20 percent",
  },
  {
    question: "Which city was once known as Yeddo?",
    option1: "Moscow",
    option2: "Tokyo",
    option3: "Toledo",
    option4: "Paris",
    answer: "Tokyo",
  },
  {
    question: "Weathering by abrasion occurs by agents such as:",
    option1: "Gravity",
    option2: "Tree roots",
    option3: "Air",
    option4: "wind and water",
    answer: "wind and water",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which country's Antarctic claim covers the greatest swath of longitude?",
    option1: "New Zealand",
    option2: "Argentina",
    option3: "Australia",
    option4: "United Kingdom",
    answer: "Australia",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In what year did Garfield High School become the first Seattle high school with more than 50 percent nonwhite student body?",
    option1: "1969",
    option2: "1957",
    option3: "1963",
    option4: "1955",
    answer: "1957",
  },
  {
    question: "The small Republic of San Marino is surrounded by?",
    option1: "Italy",
    option2: "Spain",
    option3: "Morocco",
    option4: "France",
    answer: "Italy",
  },
  {
    question: "In what year did the U.S. invade Grenada?",
    option1: "1985",
    option2: "1989",
    option3: "1983",
    option4: "1982",
    answer: "1983",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the largest freshwater lake in the world?",
    option1: "Lake Huron",
    option2: "Lake Michigan",
    option3: "Lake Victoria",
    option4: "Lake Baikal",
    answer: "Lake Baikal",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which telescope was the largest in the world when it was built in 1948?",
    option1: "Mayall",
    option2: "Hale",
    option3: "Sagan",
    option4: "Hubble",
    answer: "Hale",
  },
  {
    question: "Which country contains most of the Kalahari desert?",
    option1: "Botswana",
    option2: "Angola",
    option3: "Congo",
    option4: "Djibouti",
    answer: "Botswana",
  },
  {
    question: "In science, the “L” in the acronym LASER stands for what?",
    option1: "Lense",
    option2: "Lumen",
    option3: "Light",
    option4: "Lesering",
    answer: "Light",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In 336 B.C., Alexander the Great succeeded his father as the leader of what kingdom?",
    option1: "Macedonian",
    option2: "Assyrian",
    option3: "Ottoman",
    option4: "Phoenician",
    answer: "Macedonian",
  },
  {
    question: "In which country would one find the Tees-Exe line?",
    option1: "France",
    option2: "Denmark",
    option3: "United Kingdom",
    option4: "Sweden",
    answer: "United Kingdom",
  },
  {
    question: "Which branch of mathematics does topology fall under?",
    option1: "Computer science",
    option2: "Calculus",
    option3: "Physics",
    option4: "Geometry",
    answer: "Geometry",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What food is traditionally served during Christmas festivities in Japan?",
    option1: "Salmon roe",
    option2: "Microwave popcorn",
    option3: "A decorated cake",
    option4: "Miso soup",
    answer: "A decorated cake",
  },
  {
    question: "Rock Steady: A Story of Noah's Ark was written by",
    option1: "Sting",
    option2: "The Rock",
    option3: "David Crosby",
    option4: "Elvis",
    answer: "Sting",
  },
  {
    question: "Which country controls Aruba?",
    option1: "United Kingdom",
    option2: "Netherlands",
    option3: "United States",
    option4: "Spain",
    answer: "Netherlands",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What US president's news conferences were called “Best matinee in Town”?",
    option1: "John F. Kennedy",
    option2: "Jimmy Carter",
    option3: "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
    option4: "Lyndon B. Johnson",
    answer: "John F. Kennedy",
  },
];
